Lori L Berti

(720)232-8840 (cell) (303)680-8346(home) lberti@msn.com

A self-motivated, highly qualified professional with over twenty-one years of experience in the financial services industry including ten with a major insurance software company. Background includes providing business and technical support for several high profile clients. Self-starter; results-oriented problem solver with strong organizational skills.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Development Program (Denver, Colorado)

Student - April 2019 to Present

- 10 hours/week class time and 20+hours/week homework
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, JQuery, Git, AJAX, Express, Node, SQL, Heroku

Computer Sciences Corporation, (Acquired PMSC/Mynd/Cybertek) Englewood, Colorado

Programmer Analyst (Property and Casualty Group) - January 2006 to Present

- Manage Production, Unit, System, Development environments on a daily basis for multiple clients.
- Implement new and modify existing documents based on client's requirement that includes triggering and variable information to populate the form.
- Modify system files which update coding information to meet customer's needs based on client's requirements and production issues reported.
- Perform Electronic Forms Composition using a CSC Value Added system.

Associate Business Consultant (Life Insurance Group) - February 1998 to January 2006

- Analyzed and implemented a consolidation of three platforms onto one. It required two of the platforms upgraded to the current release level. Solely responsible for the table conversion of 581 tables.
- Acted as Liaison between programmer and customer staff to define problems within existing programs.
- Gathered and documented Business and Technical Specifications based on customer proposed enhancements.
- Developed and executed test plans for conversion and upgrade projects to facilitate processing customer products.
- Tested and analyzed test results through File Maintenance Batch, Onlines, and Graphic User Interface.
- Provided hands-on CyberLife training for clients on GUI and 3270 environments.
- Wrote minor COBOL program changes to improve and modify processing on life insurance system.
- Worked on the development of a conversion tool set, responsible for identification of the data requirements for file conversions.

Conseco, (Acquired Life Partners Group) Carmel, Indiana

Controls Analyst, Trainer, Conversion Specialist - September 1996 to January 1998

- Developed and executed test plans for a conversion project. Reported and documented variances from expected results
- Trained and instructed staff on Policy Change procedures, which included tax guidelines associated with Federal and IRS guidelines.
- Developed and wrote documentation on certain job procedures for Policy Change Analyst positions.
- Assisted Senior Management by researching and providing documentation and solutions on Insurance Complaints and high profile cases associated with Policy Administration.

EDUCATION

University of Denver, Denver, Colorado Bachelor of Science in Business Administration Continuing Education – Full Stack Development 2019